Speaker: In most towns and cities round the world, the high streets are full of chain stores.
Here are some of the most popular global chain stores on our high streets now.
Zara is a Spanish fashion chain.
It is now one of the biggest clothes companies in the world.
Fun fact! Zara can create and distribute a new design in less than two weeks.
H&M is a Swedish clothes chain.
It sells quality clothes at a very good price.
Fun fact! H&M employees always celebrate the opening of a new store with a dance.
A lot of people think that Uniqlo is quite a new clothing chain,
but it actually started in Japan in 1949.
Fun fact! Uniqlo sells 50 different colours of socks.
Nike is an American chain that sells sports clothes and shoes.
It sells more than 900 million items every year.
Fun fact! The Nike symbol has its own name – it’s called the ‘Swoosh’.
The first Body Shop opened in Brighton, England, in 1976.
It sells environmentally-friendly products for the body, face, hair, and home.
Fun fact! The first Body Shop was painted dark green, not to be more eco-friendly,
but because the shop had a lot of mould and dark green was the only colour that could cover it.
Apple is an American technology company, selling phones, tablets, and computers.
Fun fact! Apple launched a clothing line in 1986, which didn’t have any success.
Chains are popular because they are familiar –
if we go to a new town or even to a different country,
we know that we can find our favourite products in these shops.